neiu.edu 2005-12-14

# NEIU Privacy Statement

|  | **Privacy Statement**  
---|---  
  
**Overview:**  
Northeastern Illinois University (NEIU) is committed to protecting the privacy of its faculty, staff, students and visitors using its web services. To this extent, NEIU will only allow tracking or collection of specific client information on its site that facilitates business transactions of the University. This Privacy Statement describes how and what information we track and collect and how it is protected.

**How and what information we track:**  
We collect information by creating cookies, the use of data collection programs, access to web based course management applications such as Blackboard and by access to library online resources. 

Cookies: We may enable "cookies." A cookie is a file of data or instructions that is placed on a client's computer by a web-site server to collect or store information about the client use of the site. These cookies are not designed to identify a person but intended to enhance navigation and the security of a client's session.

Data collection programs: These programs use web forms to collect such data for admission applications, student related services, and other client business data intended to collect such information as is necessary to provide the client with the business service requested. This type of information is collected on a voluntary basis and it is not used for any purpose other than what is originally disclosed. At times, NEIU may collect data regarding client access to its web pages for statistical purposes. This is done to measure cumulative client interest in various areas of the web site to provide better services to NEIU clients. The statistics contain no personal information and will not be used to gather such information.

Web based course management applications: These specific applications provide online interaction between and among students and faculty. Data and information available includes access to course syllabi and assignments, online course announcements, links to relevant Internet resources, and support for basic e-mail communication between instructors and students

Library online resources: Periodical indexes and other databases are accessible to Northeastern Illinois University students, faculty and staff by contractual agreement with the commercial providers of those products. Authentication by account name and password is required for access to NEIU licensed databases.

**Links to other sites and NEIU Web page hosting:**  
The NEIU website has links to other websites. When linking to another site, NEIU clients are subject to the privacy policy of that new site. Some of these sites provide web services to our clients that include grade inquiries, course management resources, and admission applications. NEIU is not responsible for the privacy practices of these agents. Please carefully review the Privacy Policy of each site you visit through NEIU links before complying with data requests. 

NEIU provides web page hosting for faculty, staff and students from which external site links are made. This web hosting does not constitute an endorsement by the University. The University is not responsible for the contents of any off-site pages referenced and specifically disclaims any and all liability from damages that may result from accessing a third party site that is linked from the NEIU website.

**Security:**  
NEIU conforms to security standards and Information Technology practices to assure the integrity of data and privacy of its clients. Such practices include authentication, monitoring, auditing and encryption. The computing infrastructure, network, and systems procedures are designed and maintained to ensure a high level of integrity and security. Access to information is restricted to faculty, staff and students who have legitimate need for the information.

Please address questions to : [webteam@neiu.edu](mailto:webteam@neiu.edu)
